小心：潜意识镇静药 目的地：坦塔罗斯流放殖民地 接收人：特立斯坦·亚当斯医生
准备传送
Ready to beam down.
传送
Energize.
出问题了，先生们？
Having trouble, gentlemen?
搞不懂问题出在哪儿，长官
I just don't understand the problem, sir.
你正把货物传往一个流放殖民地，伯克利先生
You're beaming cargo down to a penal colony, Mr. Berkeley.
- 他们开启了安全力场，长官 - 进取号呼叫坦塔罗斯流放地
- Their security force field, sir. - USS Enterprise to Tantalus Colony.
康复治疗殖民地收到，请讲
Rehab colony, come in.
请求开放安全力场，以便传送货物
Request opening in your force field for beaming down of cargo.
进取号，收到，安全屏障现已打开
Enterprise, affirmative. Our security cover is now open.
传送
Energize.
有货物要上传么？
Any incoming cargo?
就一件，长官，一些研究材料
Just one item, sir. Some research material
要送往斯德哥尔摩的中央监狱管理局
bound for the Central Bureau of Penology, Stockholm.
坦塔罗斯货物准备上传
Tantalus cargo ready to beam up.
噢，伯克利先生
Oh, Mr. Berkeley.
你得重温一下流放殖民地的
You might refamiliarize yourself with the manual
- 操作条例 - 马上重温，长官
- on penal colony procedures. - Immediately, sir.
我想你可以先把这个锁起来
I think you can take the time to lock this up first.
我会把它放进保险库
I'll get a vault assignment.
机密材料 严禁打开
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF字幕组荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：土豆爱，Nick，jc
校对：我不是小狗，kmdangdangli，xjCGI
第一季 第九集
思想之匕
舰长日志，星历2715.1
Captain's log, stardate 2715.1.
与坦塔罗斯五号行星上的流放殖民地交换了货物
Exchanged cargo with penal colony on Tantalus V.
未登陆便直接离开了
Have departed without going ashore.
我倒是挺想见一下亚当斯医生的
I would like to have met Dr. Adams.
自从采纳他的理论管理流放殖民地以来，你去过那些地方吗？
Have you been to a penal colony since they started following his theories?
- 牢笼就是牢笼，吉姆 - 老骨头，你跟不上时代了
- A cage is a cage, Jim. - You're behind the times, Bones.
他们现在更像休闲殖民地
They're more like resort colonies now.
有消息，舰长，切换至扬声器
Message, captain. Switching to speaker.
坦塔罗斯殖民地呼叫进取号
Tantalus Colony to Enterprise.
一个犯人失踪了
we are unable to locate one of our inmates.
可能有发生暴力案件的隐患
This is a potentially violent case.
很可能躲在上传给你们的箱子里
Possibly hidden in the box we beamed up to you.
再说一遍，一个犯人失踪了
Repeat. Unable to locate one of our inmates.
- 可能有发生暴力案件的隐患 - 进取号收到，待命
- This is a potentially violent case. - Enterprise acknowledging. Stand by.
3级安全警报
Security alert three.
安全警报，3级戒备，全体部门启动3级戒备
Security alert. Condition three. All sections go to alert condition three.
可能有一个入侵者登船
We may have an intruder aboard.
重复一遍，全体部门启动3级戒备，入侵者已经登船
Repeat. All sections to alert condition three. Intruder aboard.
嘿，你是轮机部门的
Hey, you from Engineering.
舰桥，C区，14层甲板
Bridge, section C, deck 14.
舰长，C区，14层甲板，发现可疑人员
Captain, section C, deck 14, reporting trouble.
有一个穿轮机员制服的人
Someone in Engineering uniform.
安全控制部，这里是舰桥，派人过来
Security control, this is the bridge. Come in.
我已控制局面，舰长，14层甲板已关闭，搜索进行中
I have them, captain. Closing off deck 14, search in progress.
安全警报，3级戒备
Security alert. Condition three.
身高约6英尺4英寸，男，40岁出头，注意防范
Approximately 6'4", male, early 40s. Approach with caution.
此人极度危险
This man extremely dangerous.
重复一遍，注意严加防范，舰桥通知完毕
Repeat, approach with extreme caution. Bridge out.
不在甲板区域，舰长，他可能已经溜出去了
Negative in the deck area, captain. He may have gotten out.
扩大搜索范围至周边区域
Expanding search to adjoining sections.
- 进取号呼叫坦塔罗斯殖民地 - 坦塔罗斯殖民地，我是亚当斯
- Enterprise to Tantalus Colony. - Tantalus Colony, Adams here.
亚当斯医生？我是寇克舰长
Dr. Adams? This is Captain Kirk.
你们的一个犯人好像登上了星舰
It appears we may have an inmate of yours aboard the ship.
一个传送员被人打昏，舰长
Transporter crewman found unconscious, captain.
货物箱开着，是空的
Cargo case open and empty.
那就肯定了，医生，他在星舰上
Make that definite, doctor. He's aboard.
十分抱歉，舰长，是我的疏忽，我再重复一遍
Terribly sorry, captain. I take all the blame. Let me repeat.
他很狡猾且相当暴力，要小心提防他
He's clever as well as extremely violent. Take all possible precautions.
我们会和你保持联系的，医生，完毕
We'll keep you posted, doctor. Kirk out.
全体部门，安全搜索进行中，报告
All sections. Security check in progress. Report.
敌人行踪不明，收到
Over-changer, affirmative.
确认警报级别，各部门展开安全行动
Confirm alert conditions. Section operational ready.
真有趣
Interesting.
你们地球人四千年来，老是赞美有组织的暴力
You Earth people glorify organised violence for 40 centuries,
却用监狱对付个体的施暴行为
but you imprison those who employ it privately.
如此说来，你们族人知道如何应对暴力咯
And, of course, your people found an answer.
我们摒除情绪，医生
We disposed of emotion, doctor.
没有情绪化，就没有暴力倾向
Where there's no emotion, there's no motive for violence.
舰长在哪？
Where's the captain?
- 你们中哪一个是舰长？ - 我是寇克舰长
- Which one of you is the captain? - I'm Captain Kirk.
我叫…
My name is...
凡·格尔德
...Van Gelder.
我请求庇护
I want asylum.
用枪指着我吗？
At gunpoint?
我要你先答应我
I want your promise first.
保证不会把我送回去
Your word that you won't take me back there.
回坦塔罗斯
To Tantalus.
我不答应
No promises.
- 把武器给我 - 不
- Give me the weapon. - No.
不，不，我不回去
No. No, I'm not going back.
我会先让你的飞船瘫痪，想清楚，舰长
I'll disable your vessel first. You choose, captain.
我会摧毁飞船的控制面板
I'll destroy your control panel.
把他带到医务室
Take him to Sickbay.
返航
Reverse course.
返回坦塔罗斯殖民地
Head back for Tantalus Colony.
不正常，意料之中
Abnormal, of course.
不是精神分裂症，不是组织损伤
It's not schizophrenia, tissue damage
也不是我熟悉的任何情况，吉姆，带他到这儿后
or any condition I'm acquainted with, Jim. And after getting him here,
用了3倍剂量的镇静剂才让他稳定下来
it took almost a triple dose of sedative to put him under.
报告称他相当健谈
The report said he was quite talkative.
但没什么实质内容
But not very informative.
刚说起一件事，好像马上就忘了
Claim one thing, then he seemed to forget,
然后又开始说别的事
and then he'd start to claim something else.
但话里不时透露出一星半点的真相
But always with just a ring of truth in it.
我想要好好研究一下，吉姆
I'd sure like to study this one, Jim.
- 他不再是我们的麻烦了，老骨头 - 你这个自以为是、乱摁按钮的狗屁军官
- Not our problem, Bones. - You smug, button-pushing brass hat.
置身事外，那就是你的处事方式吗？
Wash your hands of it. Is that your system?
你们俩都自信满满，是吧？了不起的专业人士
You're both quite sure of yourselves, aren't you? Quite expert.
把他带回去，让别人操心吧
Take him back. Let someone else worry about him.
- 你说你的名字叫什么？ - 我的名字？
- What did you say your name was? - My name?
我的名字是…
My name is--
西蒙…
Simon...
…凡·格尔德
...Van Gelder.
我是主管…
I was the director of--
主管…
Director...
…坦塔罗斯殖民地的主管
...at the Tantalus Colony.
明白我说的了吧？
See what I mean?
我毕业于…
I was graduate of--
于…
Of--
我是助理…
I was assistant to--
我知道的
I knew.
但是他们已经擦除了
But they've erased it.
擦除了？
Erased?
编辑了
Edited.
调整了
Adjusted.
颠覆了我
Subverted me.
但我不会忘记的！我不会忘记的！
But I won't forget! I won't forget!
你是那么愚昧无知，你认为我属于那里，对吗？
You're so blind ignorant. You believe I belong back there, don't you?
不管死活，噢，我不会让你送我回去的
Dead or alive. Well, I won't let you take me back.
我不去，我宁愿去死
I'm not going. I'll die first.
你听见了吗？我不去
Do you hear? I'm not going.
不，不，不
No. No. No
估计多久到坦塔罗斯？
Estimating arrival to Tantalus?
57分钟30秒，舰长
Fifty-seven minutes, 30 seconds, captain.
什么让你这么着迷？
What's so fascinating?
船上信息库的一盘身份鉴定磁带
An identification tape from our ship's library
关于西蒙·凡·格尔德医生的
on Dr. Simon Van Gelder.
- 凡·格尔德医生？ - 凡·格尔德医生，舰长
- Dr. Van Gelder? - Dr. Van Gelder, captain.
没错，这是一盘完整的有关他身份证明的磁带
No mistake. There's a full ID tape on him.
- 他在坦塔罗斯殖民地工作多久了？ - 6个月前
- Committed to Tantalus Colony when? - Assigned there.
他被任命为亚当斯医生的助理
Six months ago, as Dr. Adams' associate.
星舰呼叫地面，坦塔罗斯殖民地
Ship to surface. Tantalus Colony.
- 呼叫频道已开通，长官 - 进取号呼叫坦塔罗斯殖民地
- Hailing frequency's open, sir. - USs Enterprise to Tantalus Colony.
坦塔罗斯
Tantalus.
我是寇克舰长，我想和亚当斯医生通话
This is Captain Kirk. I'd like to speak to Dr. Adams.
稍等，进取号
stand by, Enterprise.
寇克舰长，我是亚当斯医生
Captain Kirk. Dr. Adams here.
亚当斯医生，关于你们逃脱的犯人
Dr. Adams, regarding your escaped man.
凡·格尔德医生还好吧？你的人没受伤吧？
Is Dr. Van Gelder all right? And your people, no injuries?
无人伤亡，先生
No casualties, sir.
- 这个人是西蒙·凡·格尔德医生吗？ - 是啊，当然是他
- This man is Dr. Simon Van Gelder? - Yes, of course.
你确定他没事吗？我们一直非常担心
You're certain he's all right? we've been very concerned.
- 他处于狂暴状态… - 他并未受到伤害，先生
- In the violent state he's in-- - No harm to him, sir.
我希望你能通报一下他的情况
We thought you might enlighten us as to his condition.
他一直在做一项实验，舰长
He'd been doing some experimental work, captain.
是一种实验性光束，我们希望用它来改造那些顽固的罪犯
An experimental beam we'd hoped might rehabilitate incorrigibles.
凡·格尔德感到他没有道德上的权利
Van Gelder felt he hadn't the moral right
让别人暴露在他没有亲身试验过的光线之下
to expose another man to something he hadn't tried on his own person.
- 真是个悲剧，医生… - 吉姆
- Tragedy, doctor-- - Jim.
听起来不太像真话
That doesn't quite ring true.
亚当斯医生，请稍等
Dr. Adams, please stand by.
什么意思
Explain.
我不相信亚当斯
I don't believe him.
我无法解释，但我研究那个病人越多…
I can't explain it, but the more I study that patient--
你不相信他，但你又解释不清
You don't believe him, and you can't explain it.
老骨头，你可知道，过去的20年里
Bones, are you aware that in the last 20 years
亚当斯医生为改革监狱
Dr. Adams has done more to revolutionise,
改造囚犯，改善囚犯待遇所作出的努力
to humanize prisons and the treatment of prisoners
比40个世纪以来，全部其他人所做的都要多吗？
than all the rest of humanity had done in 40 centuries?
我去过那些流放殖民地
I've been to those penal colonies
自从按照亚当斯的理论管理
since they've begun following his methods,
- 它们不再是牢笼了 - 吉姆
- and they're not cages anymore. - Jim.
它们成了医治心理疾病的干净、舒适的医院
They're clean, decent hospitals for sick minds.
- 吉姆，听我说… - 绅士们
- Jim, listen-- - Gentlemen.
我建议问问亚当斯医生，是否要求凡·格尔德回去
I suggest you ask Dr. Adams if he wants Van Gelder returned.
- 亚当斯医生，关于凡·格尔德 - 是的，舰长
- Dr. Adams, regarding Van Gelder. - Yes, captain.
我可以打听一下你们的巡航目的地吗？
May I enquire about your patrol destinations?
你们路过的地方，有比我们更高级的医疗设备吗？
Are you passing near any hospital facilities superior to ours?
我当然希望凡·格尔德得到最好的治疗
I'd like Van Gelder to have the best possible treatment, of course.
谢谢，医生，我会和船上的医生沟通一下，稍等
Thank you, doctor. I'll take it up with the ship's surgeon. Stand by.
老骨头，接招吧，你有更好的地方推荐吗？
Well, Bones, you've got the ball. You care to recommend a better place?
哪有什么高级设备，他又不是不知道
There are no superior facilities. He knows that.
但问题在于
But that's not the question.
如果下面出了什么不寻常的状况…
If something unusual is going on down there--
你这只是假设，医生
An assumption, doctor.
我必须在医疗日志上记下所有合理的疑虑
I'm required to enter any reasonable doubts into my medical log.
那就需要你在你的日志中给出回答
That requires you to answer in your log.
抱歉，吉姆
Sorry, Jim.
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams.
这相当为难啊
This is rather embarrassing.
根据星舰的规章制度
By strict interpretation of our starship regulation,
我得介入调查此事
I'm required to initiate an investigation of this
- 如此，才能酌情上报… - 不用道歉，寇克舰长
- so that a proper report-- - No need to apologise, Captain Kirk.
实际上，如果你下来亲自察看一下
In fact, I'd take it as a personal favour
反倒是在帮我的忙呢
if you'd beam down and look into it yourself.
你肯定也知道我们这儿的访客其实不多
I'm sure you realise we don't get too many visitors here.
噢，我…
Oh, I--
舰长，如果你能尽量少带随员
Captain, I would appreciate it
我将不甚感激
if you could come down with a minimum staff.
本殖民地必须尽量减少与外界的联系
We're forced to limit outside contact as much as possible.
知道了，医生
Affirmative, doctor.
我以前去过那些康复治疗殖民地，进取号通话完毕
I've visited rehab colonies before. Enterprise out.
如果可能，给我在你的部门找个
Find me someone in your department with psychiatric
在精神病学和监狱管理学方面都有经验的人
and penology experience, if possible.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
舰长日志，星历2715.2
Captain's log, stardate 2715.2.
r星舰运行在坦塔罗斯五号行星的同步轨道上
Standard orbit, planet Tantalus V.
任务：根据船医的医疗日志
Mission: Routine investigation and report
我们将进行一次例行调查和报告
as per ship's surgeon's medical log.
看来这一次，我终于得见亚当斯医生一面了
As for my last entry, it seems I will get to meet Dr. Adams at last.
但我宁愿是因别的缘由，而与他会面
However, I would have preferred other circumstances.
医务室
Sickbay.
报告情况，医生
Report, doctor.
凡·格尔德仍处于躁狂状态，舰长
Van Gelder is still violently agitated, captain.
那在我调查完毕之前，你是打算把他留在这儿吗？
And you'd prefer to keep him here until I complete my investigation, anyway.
我们应该这么做，吉姆
I believe we should, Jim.
对了，舰长，我给你安排了专业顾问
Oh, I'm assigning you technical aid, captain.
我们有个心理学家在康复治疗领域有一定经验
One of our psychiatrists does have a background in rehabilitative therapy.
诺埃尔医生正在传送室待命
Dr. Noel. Standing by in the Transporter Room now.
谢谢，医生，到传送室去，史波克先生
Thank you, doctor. Bridge out. Mr. Spock.
- 坐标？ - 已经锁定，长官，传送准备就绪
- Coordinates? - Locked in, sir. Ready to beam down.
我是海伦·诺埃尔医生，舰长
Dr. Helen Noel, captain.
我们见过
We've met.
你不记得了吗？
Don't you remember?
- 在科学实验室的圣诞派对上 - 是的，我记得
- The Science Lab Christmas party. - Yes, I remember.
- 你姗姗来迟 - 没错，我记得
- You dropped in. - Yes. Yes, I remember.
有问题吗，舰长？
Problem, captain?
史波克先生，转告麦考伊
Mr. Spock, you tell McCoy that she had better check out
他最好是给我找对了上佳人选
as the best assistant I ever had.
- 传送 - 传送
Energize.
应该是这边，医生
In here, I presume, doctor.
或许你可以简短点，叫我海伦，舰长，因为…
Perhaps it would be simpler if you called me Helen, captain, since--
现在可不是在开派对
This is another time, another place and another situation.
当然，舰长
Of course, captain.
升降机
Elevator.
正在快速下降
And going down quite a way.
心脏差点的人可受不了这个
I wouldn't recommend it for weak hearts.
你好，寇克舰长
Hello, Captain Kirk.
- 这位是…？ - 海伦·诺埃尔医生
- And...? - Dr. Helen Noel.
- 见到您本人很荣幸，医生 - 谢谢，谢谢，舰长
- A pleasure to finally meet you, sir. - Thank you. Thank you, captain.
- 欢迎来到恶魔岛，医生 - 或许你可以叫我海伦，医生
- Welcome to Devil's Island, doctor. - Perhaps you'll call me Helen, doctor.
医生这，医生那，我们都搞不清是在说谁呢
With so many titles around, we're not gonna be sure who's talking to who.
- 没错，请进 - 谢谢
- I shall indeed. Won't you? - Thank you.
按规定我要被搜身缴械，对吧
I believe regulations call for me to check my weapon.
噢不，对你来说没这必要，舰长
Oh, no, no. That won't be necessary in your case, captain.
只要别拿出来就好
Just keep it out of sight, huh?
我知道你们要是没有武器傍身的话，会浑身不自在
I know you people feel as naked without a weapon
就像我们没带医疗包一样
as we do without a medikit.
来干一杯吧，好吗？
A small toast. Do you mind?
真是蓬荜生辉啊，坦塔罗斯星今日有贵客来访
It's such a great day for us here on Tantalus when we have visitors,
- 先不论为何而来 - 医生…
- no matter what the excuse. - Doctor--
得了，舰长，你上次通话时已经道过谦了，别再提了
Oh, now, captain, you made your apology from upstairs. Now forget it.
信号被力场屏蔽了，舰长
I don't think you'll be able to get through the security screen, captain.
请稍等
Just a second.
可以了，现在试试吧
Here, now try it.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 这里是进取号，我是史波克
- Kirk to Enterprise. Come in. - Enterprise. Spock here.
传送坐标设定得非常精确，史波克先生
Your landing coordinates were right on the nose, Mr. Spock.
我们已安全到达，现正与亚当斯医生在一起，报告结束
We arrived safely, and we're here with Dr. Adams right now. Kirk out.
收到了，舰长，进取号呼叫结束
Affirmative, captain. Enterprise out.
哈，莱西，请进
Lethe. Come in.
莱西，这是寇克舰长和海伦·诺埃尔医生
Lethe, this is Captain Kirk and Dr. Helen Noel.
莱西之前来我们这里接受康复治疗
Lethe came to us for rehabilitation and stayed on as a therapist.
但现在已成为了一名优秀的治疗师
And a very good one too, I might add.
我热爱我的工作
I love my work.
你可以随便问，舰长
Go right ahead, captain.
你来这之前…
Before you came here...?
与现在截然不同，那时我内心曾充满邪恶
I was another person. Malignant, hateful.
能告诉我你犯了什么罪吗？
May I ask what crime you committed?
这有什么关系吗？我已经不再是以前的我
Does it matter? That person no longer exists.
舰长，我们治疗方法的一部分，就是让患者忘掉过去
Part of our cure, if you will, captain, is to bury the past.
如非必要，为什么要让一个人背负沉重的过去…
Why should a person go on living with unbearable memories if there's no--?
我想你也应该有同感吧，医生…
Oh, I feel quite sure that you'd concur with me in that, doctor--
海伦
Helen.
对心理治疗来说，改变记忆模式是必不可少的
A shifting of memory patterns is basic to psychotherapy.
没错，现在来干一杯吧
Yes. And now to the toast.
请勿介意我们的放纵，莱西，来，舰长
You'll forgive us, Lethe? There you are, captain.
敬全人类
To all Mankind.
愿宇宙不再广袤冷漠
May we never find space so vast,
愿所有星球不再天寒地冻
planets so cold,
愿不再有空虚的心灵
heart and mind so empty
无法感受爱和温暖
that we cannot fill them with love and warmth.
这次参观真是令我印象深刻，医生
Quite a tour, doctor. Very impressive.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿，卡尔
Hey, Karl.
- 医生？ - 怎么了
- Doctor? - Yes.
我就怕你会问这个，舰长
I was afraid you'd ask about this, captain.
要知道，人们都不喜欢谈论失败
One doesn't like to talk about their personal failures, you know.
这只是一个出了点小差错的实验项目
Just an experiment that went wrong, I'm afraid.
我可以看看吗？
May I see it?
舰长，如果一个项目不成功，也就失去了研究价值…
Captain, if something hasn't worked out and therefore has no scientific value--
我们能让亚当斯医生来做决定吗？
Shall we leave it up to the doctor?
既然你让我跟来当顾问，舰长…
Since you brought me down here for advice, captain--
医生，身为舰长，其中一个特权就是
One of the advantages of being a captain, doctor,
虽然垂询，但不是非得接受建议
is being able to ask for advice without necessarily having to take it.
我看这一轮得判舰长赢，海伦
I think I'll have to award that round to the captain, Helen.
你这是胳膊拧不过大腿，好吧，那就看看吧
You're fighting over your weight. All right, let's take a look.
我不是罪犯
I'm not a criminal.
我不需要…
I do not require...
…神经中和器
...neural neutraliser.
神经中和器？
Neural neutraliser?
你能解释一下吗，凡·格尔德医生？
Can you explain that, Dr. Van Gelder?
一个房间
A room.
一个装置
A device.
门
Door.
控制面板
Control panel.
天花板
Ceiling.
一个装置
A device.
- 光！光！ - 在那个房间里发生了什么？
- A light! Light! - This room, what happens there?
神经中和器
A neural neutraliser.
尚处于试验阶段，其实我们并不指望能获得多大成果
Experimental. Actually, we don't expect to get much use out of it at all.
来自上面的光线可以中和脑电波
That beam from above neutralises brain waves.
让病人的心智平和下来，不会对他造成伤害，当然
Relaxes the patient's mind. Does him no harm, of course,
- 效果只是暂时的 - 有个问题，医生
- and the effects are only temporary. - One question, doctor.
- 如果它没有优点… - 为什么还要继续使用，对吧，舰长？
- If it doesn't do any good-- - Why do we go on using it, captain?
希望，是的，我们心怀一丝希望
Hope. Yes. Yes, there's always that slight chance that
希望它能对一些暴力倾向较严重的患者起作用
it might do some good in the more violent cases.
镇静剂虽然是好东西，舰长
Tranquilizers are fine, captain.
但不断地往人的血管里注入化学药物…
But to continually pump chemicals into a person's bloodstream--
跟我想得一样，海伦，我们继续参观吧？
Exactly my point, Helen. Yes. Shall we?
- 这怎么用？ - 很简单
- How does it work? - Quite simple.
这里是开关
Off-on switches.
这边的旋钮控制着
The large control here changes the strength
脑波中和光线的强度
of the brain neutralising beam.
舰长
Captain.
你让我想起过去一位怀疑论者
You remind me of the ancient sceptic who demanded of the wise old sage
他单脚站立，要求智者把所有的智慧在片刻间倾囊相授
to be taught all the world's wisdom while standing on one foot.
人们曾在地球上对这种光线疗法做过试验，舰长
Beam neutralising has been experimented with on Earth, captain.
我对这种设备并不熟悉
I'm not acquainted with this particular style of equipment,
但我可以向你保证，亚当斯医生
but I can assure you that Dr. Adams
可不是在制造折磨病人的刑具
has not created a chamber of horrors here.
我并没有说他有这么做
I didn't mean to suggest that he had.
医生，我之所以会问
The reason I asked, sir,
是因为你还没有说明凡·格尔德医生是在哪儿受的伤
was you haven't mentioned where Dr. Van Gelder's injury occurred.
就在这儿，舰长
Right here, captain.
是的
Yes.
格尔德是个很固执的人
Simon was a very stubborn man.
他能长时间暴露在现在这种强度的中和光线下
He could have sat in that room for years with the beam at that volume,
甚至强度更高也没问题，只要他肯让别人陪在旁边
or even higher. Or if he simply had someone standing by
一出现意外就关闭机器，但他并没有这么做
to snap it off in case he got into trouble. But no.
他尝试独自一人做试验，并把强度调到最高
He tried it alone and on full volume.
真是遗憾
It is a pity.
谢谢
Thank you.
你要忘记你听到的一切
You will forget all you have heard.
如果你企图回忆，即使是其中的只言片语 你也将感受到可怕的痛苦
To remember any portion of it, any word, will cause you pain.
如果你竭力去回忆，痛苦会更剧烈
Terrible pain, growing more terrible as you fight to remember.
能告诉我你现在在哪儿吗，舰长？
Can you give us your present location, captain?
在亚当斯医生的书房，怎么了，史波克先生？
In Dr. Adams' study, Mr. Spock. why?
- 你现在和亚当斯医生在一起？ - 没错
- Then you're with Dr. Adams now? - Affirmative.
舰长
Captain.
凡·格尔德提到一种治疗设备
Van Gelder has made reference to a particular treatment room.
他把它称作神经中和器
The term was "neural neutraliser."
是的，他在那里意外受了伤，我查看过那个房间
Yes, he was injured there. I've seen the room.
亚当斯医生解释了凡·格尔德的失误
Dr. Adams explained the mistake Van Gelder made.
史波克先生，还有别的问题吗？
Go ahead, Mr. Spock. Anything further?
看来你的史波克先生是一个
Your Mr. Spock sounds like a very excellent
非常优秀的大副，寇克舰长
second in command, Captain Kirk.
请让他直言，毋须忌讳
Please tell him to go ahead and speak freely.
反正我现在要去检查工作了
I have to check in with a member of my staff, anyway.
- 谢谢，亚当斯医生 - 失陪
- Thank you, Dr. Adams. - Excuse me.
稍等，史波克先生
Stand by, Mr. Spock.
亚当斯医生已经有事离开了
Dr. Adams has left with some things to attend to.
怎么了，史波克先生？
What is it, Mr. Spock?
凡·格尔德现在极度焦躁不安，舰长
Van Gelder is extremely agitated, captain,
他警告说你现在有危险
and warns that you're in danger.
他在胡说
That's foolish.
请再说一遍，舰长，我听不清楚
Please repeat, captain. I didn't receive that.
告诉麦考伊，他派来的技术顾问认为
Tell McCoy the technical expert he sent along with me
任何担忧都是多余的
insists that any concern is unjustified.
根据亚当斯的说法，凡·格尔德是自食其果
According to Adams, Van Gelder created his own problem.
他的神经突触受到了损伤
He's suffering from neural synapse damage.
他的大脑现在就像短路了一样，所以才会有幻觉
As if his brain were short-circuited. It's no wonder he's having delusions.
我是麦考伊，收到，明白
McCoy here. Received and understood.
但我们仍然心存疑虑，舰长
But we still have some doubts up here, captain.
你还有别的吩咐吗？
Can you tell us any more?
没了
Not really.
你打算什么时候回来，舰长？
when do you plan to beam back up, captain?
我想我们会在这过夜，史波克先生
I think we'll spend the night here, Mr. Spock.
不！不要…
No! No, no, no.
请你每四小时回报一次，没问题吧？
And you will continue to check in every four hours?
好的
Affirmative.
寇克呼叫结束
Kirk out.
不！不能让他们在那过夜
No! No, no, don't let them.
一定要警告你们的舰长，不，不能过夜
You must warn your captain. No. No.
别让他留在那，别让他留在那
Don't let him stay. Don't let him stay.
不要，不，不要给我打镇静剂，求你了，不要打
Don't. No, no, don't hypo me. Please, don't hypo me.
我尽量控制住自己
I'll try not to fight.
我尽量
I'll try.
但你们要听好
But you must listen.
警告你们的舰长，亚当斯医生
Warn your captain. Dr. Adam--
亚当斯医生…
Dr. Adams...
- 会摧毁… - 摧毁什么？怎么摧毁？
- ...will destroy-- - Destroy how? What?
就像死亡
Like death.
进取号日志，我是大副史波克，代理舰长
Enterprise log, First Officer Spock, acting captain.
现在，我必须使用一种古老的瓦肯技能
I must now use an ancient Vulcan technique
去探索凡·格尔德那饱受折磨的内心世界
to probe into Van Gelder's tortured mind.
史波克，只要有一丝希望，就能起点作用的吧
Spock, if there's the slightest possibility it might help.
我还从未在人类身上试过这种技术，医生
I have never used it on a human, doctor.
无论什么方法，只要能窥探这个人的思想
If there's any way we can look into this man's mind
搞清楚他说的到底是真是假…
to see if what he's saying is real or delusion--
这是一种瓦肯人独有的私秘技能
It's a hidden, personal thing to the Vulcan people.
我们种族私人生活的一部分
Part of our private lives.
听好了，史波克，吉姆·寇克可能遇到了大麻烦
Now, look, Spock, Jim Kirk could be in real trouble.
这技能到底灵不灵？
Will it work or not?
可能会有危险
It could be dangerous.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我需要改变你的神经内压和血压
It requires I make pressure changes in your nerves, your blood vessels.
你必须敞开我的心怀
You must open my mind.
让我向你发出警告，向你解释清楚
Let me warn you, explain to you.
不会影响到你的，麦考伊医生，只有我触碰到的人才会受影响
This will not affect you, Dr. McCoy. Only the person I touch.
- 这可不是催眠 - 我明白
- It is not hypnosis. - I understand.
很好，身体机能读数正变回正常水平
Good. The reading's levelling.
你开始感到一种奇妙的幸福感
You begin to feel a strange euphoria.
你的身体飘起来了
Your body floats.
是的
Yes.
我开始感觉到了
I begin to feel it.
敞开你的心怀
Open your mind.
我们一起前行
We move together.
我们的心灵相通
Our minds sharing the same thoughts.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
你觉得我们下午在这儿看到的囚犯怎么样？
What did you think of the inmates we saw here this afternoon?
你本可以等到明天早晨
You could have waited until tomorrow morning
- 再问我这个问题的 - 我等不及
- to ask me that, captain. - I didn't.
我觉得他们很幸福，改造得很好
I thought they were happy, well-adjusted.
但表情有一些木然
But a bit blank.
舰长，如果你是在质疑特里斯坦·亚当斯这种大师的理论…
Captain, if you're questioning the methods of a man like Tristan Adams--
我想再去看看那个光线治疗室
I'd like to see that treatment room again.
你说过你对光线治疗的理论略知一二？
You say you're somewhat familiar with the theory behind it?
对，略知一二
Yes, somewhat,
但如果你只是想表达你对亚当斯医生的怀疑…
but if you'd simply state any doubts you have to Dr. Adams--
要是他撒了谎，他会继续谎话连篇 到头来，我什么都发现不了
And if he's lying, he'll continue to lie, and I won't find out a thing.
唯一能找出真相的方法，就是亲眼看看那台机器是怎么工作的
The only way I can be sure is to see that machine at work.
我这样做，是不是太不切实际，太不讲究科学了，医生？
Or is that too impractical and unscientific of me, doctor?
- 怎么样？ - 来了
- Well? - Coming.
我们叫什么名字？
What is our name?
我们是谁？
Who are we?
我们是西蒙·凡·格尔德
We are Simon Van Gelder.
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams,
那个神经中和器
the neural neutraliser.
他对我们做了什么？
What did he do to us?
他能任意重塑人的心灵
He can reshape any mind he chooses.
他用它来抹去我们的记忆
He used it to erase our memories,
把他自己的想法放进去
put his own thoughts there.
他很惊讶，这机器会消耗那么多的能量
He was surprised it took so much power.
我们反抗了他，还记得吗？
We fought him, remember?
但我们是那么疲倦
But we grew so tired.
我们的心灵是那么空虚，那么无遮无拦
Our mind so blank, so open
他放进去的任何思想都变成了我们自己的思想
that any thought he placed there became our thoughts.
我们的心灵那么空虚
Our mind so empty,
像一块渴求思想的海绵
like a sponge needing thoughts,
乞求着，空虚着
begging, empty.
孤独着
Loneliness.
空虚地晾在那里，那么孤独
So lonely to be sitting there empty.
渴求着他吐出的只言片语
Wanting any word from him.
- 爱 - 是啊
- Love. - Yes.
- 恨 - 是啊
- Hate. - Yes.
- 生 - 是啊
- Live. - Yes.
- 死 - 是啊
- Die. - Yes.
空虚得那么煎熬
Such agony, to be empty.
空虚
Empty.
孤独
Lonely.
- 孤独 - 太空虚了
- Lonely. - So empty.
太空虚了
So empty.
我可不想让我的大脑受损
I have no desire to damage my brain.
这操作起来应该是安全的，是不是？
Can this be handled with reasonable safety, yes or no?
是的
Yes.
你能把握好分寸吗？
And will you be able to determine
尽量避免让光线对我造成哪怕最细微的伤害
if that beam is harming me in the slightest?
能的，舰长，我是内行
Yes, captain. I know my profession.
准备好了？
Ready?
我们试试最低强度，一两秒钟
We'll try minimum intensity. A second or two.
你准备好就开始，医生，一两秒就停
Anytime you're ready, doctor. Just for a second or two.
我们已经试过了，舰长
We already tried it for that long, captain.
什么也没发生
Nothing happened.
有事情发生了，你的表情刚刚一片空白
Something happened. Your face went completely blank.
试个无害的暗示
Try a harmless suggestion.
你很饿
You're hungry.
瞧，等结束了以后
You know, when we finally get through with this,
我得找个厨房猛吃一顿
I'd like to locate and raid a kitchen somewhere.
我把这个暗示植入了你的思想，舰长
I put that suggestion in your mind, captain.
我只是说了句你很饿
I said simply that you were hungry.
效果好得可怕，怪不得亚当斯医生遗之不用
Remarkably effective for a device that Dr. Adams was going to abandon.
- 我觉得我们应该再试试 - 对，来点不寻常的暗示
- I think we should try this again. - Yes. Pick something unusual.
不寻常的暗示，我们俩都能领会的那种
An unusual suggestion. Something we can both be sure of.
在圣诞晚会上
At the Christmas party,
我们相遇了，我们跳舞了
we met, we danced.
你说起了星星
You talked about the stars.
我现在希望事情往另外一个方向发展
I suggest now that it happened in a different way.
你一把抱起我，带我去了你的船舱
You swept me off my feet and carried me to your cabin.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
舰长，要是被你的下属撞见，你带我来了这儿…
Captain, if your crew saw you carry me here...
我的下属会发誓保守秘密
My crew is sworn to secrecy.
但是我的名声，我是说，我们还是初次见面
But my reputation. I mean, just having met like this.
当然，要是你真心喜欢我，那就另当别论
Of course, it would be different if you cared for me.
你想让我编造一个谎言？
You want me to manufacture a lie?
打包成圣诞礼物送给你？
Wrap it up as a Christmas present for you?
不
No.
我更希望你发自内心
I prefer honesty.
现在，寇克舰长会来一次完全的真情流露
Now Captain Kirk is going to have a complete demonstration.
我希望他心里不要留存任何疑虑
I want there to be no doubts whatsoever in his mind.
你疯狂地爱上了海伦，舰长
You're madly in love with Helen, captain.
你为了她，不惜撒谎，行骗，偷窃
You'd lie, cheat, steal for her.
- 宁愿牺牲你的事业，你的名声 - 不，医生，不
- Sacrifice your career, your reputation. - No, doctor. No.
痛苦啊，你感觉到了吗，舰长？
The pain. Do you feel it, captain?
你必须得到她，不然痛苦会更加剧烈
You must have her, or the pain grows worse.
渴望得到她的痛苦
The pain, the longing for her.
海伦
Helen.
你已经爱上她很多年了，舰长
For years you've loved her, captain.
- 很多年 - 很多年了，我一直爱着你
- For years. - For years. I've loved you.
你必须一直记好了，舰长
You must continue to remember that, captain.
现在她走了
And now she's gone.
海伦
Helen.
海伦，别走
Helen, don't go.
我需要你，海伦
I need you, Helen.
现在，舰长，你必须拿出你的相位武器
Now, captain, you must take your phaser weapon
把它扔在地上
and drop it on the floor.
舰长，你要是不听话，痛苦就会加剧
Captain, the pain increases unless you obey me.
我必须…
I must...
…扔掉它
...drop it.
很好，舰长
Very good, captain.
非常好，现在轮到通讯器了
Very good, indeed. And now your communicator.
把它扔在地上
Drop it on the floor.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
寇克…
Kirk...
…呼叫进取号
...to Enterprise.
不，医生！不！
No, Doctor! No!
你已经离开了治疗室，舰长
They've taken you from the room, captain.
你现在在自己的房间里
You're in your own quarters now.
海伦
Helen.
海伦，我已经爱上你很多年了
Helen, for years I've loved you.
海伦
Helen.
- 回想一下 - 我爱你
- Try to remember. - I've loved you.
- 他把这些想法强行植入你的思想 - 很多年了
- He placed all that in your mind. - For years.
回想一下，亚当斯医生从我手中夺占了控制台
Remember. Dr. Adams took the controls away from me.
你回想起那种痛苦了吗？他的声音，想起来了？
Do you remember the pain? And then his voice? Remember?
嗯
Yes.
我想起来了
I remember.
海伦
Helen.
看
Look.
通风管道
The duct.
帮忙拉一下
Give me a hand here. Pull.
空调系统
Air conditioning.
这肯定连接到其他通风管道和隧道
It has to connect with other ducts and tunnels.
你爬进去找一找，它可能通向配电室
You can get through this. It might lead to the power supply.
短路的话，安全力场会被切断
Short-circuited, it would cut off the security force field.
你之前培训过超高功率电路的知识吗？
Have you had any training in hyper-power circuits?
没有
No.
兆伏级
Megavoltage.
一旦失手碰错电线，你就没命了
Touch the wrong line, and you're dead.
管它是什么，总不会比亚当斯的光线治疗室更糟
Anything's better than Adams' treatment room.
又到治疗时间了？
Time for another treatment?
请不要反抗我，舰长
Please don't fight me, captain.
要是你怀疑我的话，只会加剧痛苦
The pain only gets worse when you doubt me.
- 你完全信任我 - 我信任你
- You believe in me completely. - I believe in you.
而且你完全信赖我
And you trust me completely.
我…
I...
…信赖你
...trust you.
棒极了，舰长，我得表扬你
Excellent, captain. I compliment you.
你知道吗，上回凡·格尔德医生
Do you know Dr. Van Gelder was down on his hands and knees,
可是双手双膝跪地，痛得一塌糊涂呢？
sobbing at this point?
太令我满意了
It's so gratifying.
我可真幸运，实验的样本总是如此优异
I'm so fortunate to have had a couple of excellent specimens to work with.
我从中学到了很多
I've learned a great deal.
那个女医生，她不见了，亚当斯医生
The woman doctor. She's gone, Dr. Adams.
立刻通知安全人员，莱西
Notify security at once, Lethe.
- 她在哪儿，舰长？ - 我…
- Where is she, captain? - I--
- 不知道 - 海伦去哪儿了？
- Don't know. - Where did you send her?
给了她什么指令？
And with what instructions?
我…
I...
不知道
...don't know.
危险 勿碰
- 紧急通道D - 没用的，史波克先生
- Emergency channel D. - It's no good, Mr. Spock.
- 我无法突破他们的力场 - 再试试
- I can't break through their force field. - Keep trying.
主高压电源
把他放回椅子上，伊莱，找到那个女的
Get him back in the chair, Eli. And find that girl.
史波克先生，力场消失了
Mr. Spock, the force field is gone.
我能直接把你送到故障源头
I can send you right to the source of the interruption.
叫上一些安全人员，跟我一起走
Get some security people and follow me down.
传送
Energize.
安全屏障
进取号，我是史波克，力场已经被关闭了
Enterprise, this is Spock. Force field has been eliminated.
舰长
Captain.
舰长？
Captain?
- 海伦，你没事吧？ - 没事
- Helen, are you all right? - Yes.
这样是不对的，舰长
Oh, this isn't right, captain.
你这样是亚当斯医生干的
Dr. Adams did this to you.
亚当斯医生？
Dr. Adams?
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams.
治疗室，跟我来
The treatment room. Follow me.
吉姆
Jim.
电源开启了
The power came on.
他死了，舰长
He's dead, captain.
仪器的强度还不足以致命
The machine wasn't on high enough to kill.
但他独自一人暴露在光线下面
But he was alone.
能想象心灵被那种东西掏空吗？
Can you imagine the mind emptied by that thing?
甚至连一个折磨他的人都没有？
Without even a tormentor for company?
我明白
I understand.
所有部门，正在检查安全状况，报告
All sections. Security check in progress. Report.
舰长，有一条来自坦塔罗斯殖民地的信息
Oh, captain, there was a message from Tantalus Colony, sir.
凡·格尔德发来的
It was from Van Gelder.
他想告诉你光线治疗室被拆除了
He thought you'd like to know the treatment room had been dismantled,
设备被摧毁了
the equipment destroyed.
谢谢
Thank you.
很难相信人会因空虚而死
It's hard to believe that a man could die of loneliness.
要是你坐进那间屋子，就知道什么感受了
Not when you've sat in that room.
带我们离开轨道，史波克先生
Take us out of orbit, Mr. Spock.
1级曲速前进
Ahead warp factor 1.
收到，舰长，1级曲速前进
Acknowledged, captain. Warp factor 1.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏